[{"question":"An Op-Amp is designed in which order","answers":{"a":"Additional gain stage- Differential Amplification stage - low output impedance stage","b":"Differential Amplification stage- Additional gain stage - low output impedance stage","c":"Low output impedance stage - Differential Amplification stage - Additional gain stage","d":"Low output impedance stage - Additional gain stage - Differential Amplification stage"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"Usually, the voltage gain can be expressed in terms of","answers":{"a":"Volts","b":"Bel","c":"Decibel","d":"None of the above"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"In differential-mode signals operation of differential amplifier","answers":{"a":"Opposite polarity signals are applied to the inputs","b":"The gain is one","c":"The outputs are of different amplitudes","d":"Only one supply voltage is used"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"An Op-Amp has an input offset current of 20 nA and input bias current of 80 nA. Find the values of two base currents.","answers":{"a":"90 nA and 70 nA","b":"90 nA and 65 nA","c":"70 nA and 54 nA","d":"70 nA and 50 nA"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"The use of negative feedback in an op amp is that it","answers":{"a":"Reduces the voltage gain of an op-amp","b":"Makes the op amp oscillate","c":"Increases the input impedance and bandwidth","d":"Both options a and c"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"With zero volts on both inputs, an OP-amp ideally should have an output________.","answers":{"a":"Equal to the positive supply voltage","b":"Equal to the negative supply voltage","c":"Equal to zero","d":"Equal to CMRR"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"A certain non inverting amplifier has Ri of 1 kΩ and Rf of 100 kΩ. The closed-loop voltage gain is ________.","answers":{"a":"100000","b":"1000","c":"101","d":"100"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"A voltage follower ________","answers":{"a":"Has a voltage gain of 1","b":"Is non inverting amplifier","c":"Has no feedback resistor","d":"Has all of these"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"An Op-Amp amplifier is being used to amplify an input signal to a peak voltage of 100 mV. What is the maximum operating frequency of the amplifier? The slew rate is 0.5 V/µs.","answers":{"a":"456 kHz","b":"572 kHz","c":"796 kHz","d":"854 kHz"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"A certain inverting amplifier has a closed loop voltage gain of 25. The op amp has an open-loop voltage gain of 100,000. If an op amp with an open-loop voltage gain of 200,000 is substituted in the arrangement, the closed loop gain","answers":{"a":"Doubles","b":"Drops to 12.5","c":"Remains at 25","d":"Increases slightly"},"correctAnswer":"c"}]
